<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>learning on Alexander Saavedra</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/tags/learning/</link><description>Recent content in learning on Alexander Saavedra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awsaavedra.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultralearning</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ultralearning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ultralearning/</guid><description>Background We live in a time when you can go on the internet and read about most things to some level. So can you learning the equivalent to getting an undergraduate degree from a top university? Scott Young set out on a bold project of obtaining the equivalent knowledge of an undergraduate Computer Science degree from MIT in a year. He called this project the MIT Challenge. Did he succeed in this challenge?</description></item><item><title>The Willpower Instinct</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-willpower-instinct/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-willpower-instinct/</guid><description>Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5BXuZL1HAg
Sleep intervention — sleep more
mindfulness meditation + Physical exercise
Goal: Make willpower system (prefrontal cortex) bigger and better connected
Low glycemic plant based diet is ideal
Feeling guilty actually drains willpower so instead&amp;hellip;self-compassion message
Mindfulness of what you are thinking and feeling
Common humanity—everyone makes mistakes
Encouragement over criticism
learning how to talk to yourself as a good person, encouraging, and being nice</description></item><item><title>Learning How to Learn</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</guid><description>Metaskills Part 1: Learning to Learn Introduction Some of you may be aware where I picked up the term “metaskills” from, but I’ll state it anyway: Marty Neumeier’s book _Metaskills: Five Talents for the Robotic Age. _What is a metaskill? The basic idea is that a metaskill is a general skill that can be applied to numerous fields and disciplines. I thought the most important was, of course, the metaskill of all metaskills, learning to learn.</description></item></channel></rss>