<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>health on Alexander Saavedra</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/tags/health/</link><description>Recent content in health on Alexander Saavedra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:30:02 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awsaavedra.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daily Routine</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/daily-routine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:30:02 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/daily-routine/</guid><description>As a followup to the Daily Lifestyle Checklist here is a simplified daily routine I follow. All the disclaimers apply.
24-Hour Weekday Schedule 🌅 Morning (6:00 - 8:00) 6:00-6:10 | Wake Up &amp; Hygiene Brush teeth with electric toothbrush Brush tongue Wash face Apply creams: lotions then SPF for face, hands, neck 6:10-7:10 | Morning Routine Drink 2 cups of water Stretch Get outside to walk for 15-30 minutes Sauna: 10-20 minutes Head and pants protection; cold water or ice shorts and cap Meditation in sauna during this time 7:45-8:00 | Breakfast (Fasting Ends) Beverages:</description></item><item><title>Longevity Forever</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/longevity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:55:20 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/longevity/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The joy cry resolved into a jubilating chant: “Long live the king! Long live us all!” The king’s advisors, like everybody that night, were as happy as children; they embraced each other and congratulated the king: “We did it! We did it!”
But the king answered in a broken voice: “Yes, we did it, we killed the dragon today. But damn, why did we start so late? This could have been done five, maybe ten years ago!</description></item><item><title>Increasing Happiness</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/increasing-happiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 22:57:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/increasing-happiness/</guid><description>The Science of Happiness While taking the science of well being course on coursera I decided to take the course quite seriously. For one, I started without taking any of my baseline assumptions for granted and applied my skepticism as best as I could to &amp;ldquo;commong knowledge&amp;rdquo; ways of looking at happiness.
Overall the course was a good start on a life long journey to find meaning and happiness.</description></item><item><title>Daily Lifestyle Checklist</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/daily-lifestyle-checklist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/daily-lifestyle-checklist/</guid><description>Disclaimer DISCLAIMER: THIS WEBSITE DOES NOT PROVIDE MEDICAL ADVICE The information, including but not limited to, text, graphics, images and other material contained on this website are for informational purposes only. No material on this site is intended to be a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. Always seek the advice of your physician or other qualified health care provider with any questions you may have regarding a medical condition or treatment and before undertaking a new health care regimen, and never disregard professional medical advice or delay in seeking it because of something you have read on this website.</description></item></channel></rss>