<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Alexander Saavedra</title>
    <link>https://awsaavedra.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Alexander Saavedra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awsaavedra.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Criticize by Creating</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/create/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/create/</guid>
      <description>Copernicus by Stanislaw Szukalski
&amp;ldquo;The moment he [Galileo] was set at liberty, he looked up to the sky and down to the ground, and, stamping with his foot, in a contemplative mood, said, Eppur si muove, that is, still it moves, meaning the Earth.&amp;rdquo; ~ Giuseppe Baretti retelling 1757
To create is human, to consume is only tiny part of it.
Somewhere along the way we started being referred to as consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Spice Lattes</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/pumpkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 21:13:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/pumpkin/</guid>
      <description>Pumpkin spice is considered a very basic drink.
It would be considered a non-contrarian thing to drink.
Yet I rarely see men my age drinking pumpkin spice lattes and they both shun and avoid drinking pumpkin spice to avoid seeming&amp;hellip;whatever.
I would wager the amount of people who actually freely would drink pumpkin spice lattes would increase if it was not a taboo or made fun of.
Since 2005 I have used&amp;hellip;the spice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless Work</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/useless-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:53:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/useless-work/</guid>
      <description>Busyness is a choice. I choose to get things done, not be busy. Most actions are futile or irrelevant to your goals. Most things you care about are not being taken care of.
“I can’t help but wonder whether all this histrionic exhaustion isn’t a way of covering up the fact that most of what we do doesn’t matter.” –Tim Kreider
Do you want to get things done or be busy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longevity Forever</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/longevity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:55:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/longevity/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The joy cry resolved into a jubilating chant: “Long live the king! Long live us all!” The king’s advisors, like everybody that night, were as happy as children; they embraced each other and congratulated the king: “We did it! We did it!”
But the king answered in a broken voice: “Yes, we did it, we killed the dragon today. But damn, why did we start so late? This could have been done five, maybe ten years ago!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:39:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ai/</guid>
      <description>We refer to the question: What sort of creature man’s next successor in the supremacy of the earth is likely to be. We have often heard this debated; but it appears to us that we are ourselves creating our own successors; we are daily adding to the beauty and delicacy of their physical organisation; we are daily giving them greater power and supplying by all sorts of ingenious contrivances that self-regulating, self-acting power which will be to them what intellect has been to the human race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Idea Alpha</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/idea-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:02:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/idea-alpha/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Here’s to the crazy ones, the misfits, the rebels, the troublemakers, the round pegs in the square holes… the ones who see things differently — they’re not fond of rules… You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them, but the only thing you can’t do is ignore them because they change things… they push the human race forward, and while some may see them as the crazy ones, we see genius, because the ones who are crazy enough to think that they can change the world, are the ones who do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Quo</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/status-quo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:51:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/status-quo/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This picture is a commentary on human sacrifice as a societal practice, nothing else.
“Whenever serious and competent people need to get things done in the real world, all considerations of tradition and protocol fly out the window.” ~ Neal Stephenson
The status quo is taken seriously for many reasons, because most people are conservative in a way that few ever state or articulate completely– This convention, institution, etc. is the right way because it is the way I know best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprising Investor</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/enterprising-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 16:38:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/enterprising-investor/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer I am not an investment advisor. None of the information presented herein is intended to form the basis of any offer or recommendation or have any regard to the investment objectives, financial situation, or needs of any specific person, and that includes you, my dear reader. Everything you’re going to read is for informational purposes only. PLEASE DO NOT ASK FOR ANY FINANCIAL ADVICE, MY ANSWER IS ALWAYS “I DO NOT GIVE ADVICE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
