<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Alexander Saavedra</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Alexander Saavedra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awsaavedra.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Documentaries Worth Watching</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/documentaries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/documentaries/</guid><description>I watched a lot of documentaries, especially of artists and people who are driven into magnificient madness towards something greater than themselves.
“If you find yourself asking yourself (and your friends), &amp;ldquo;Am I really a writer? Am I really an artist?&amp;rdquo; chances are you are. The counterfeit innovator is wildly self-confident. The real one is scared to death.”
― Steven Pressfield, The War of Art
Art, especially the greatest of art, is not of utility but an expression of the human spirit.</description></item><item><title>Useless Work</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/useless-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:53:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/useless-work/</guid><description>Busyness is a choice. I choose to get things done, not be busy. Most actions are futile or irrelevant to your goals. Most things you care about are not being taken care of.
“I can’t help but wonder whether all this histrionic exhaustion isn’t a way of covering up the fact that most of what we do doesn’t matter.” –Tim Kreider
Do you want to get things done or be busy?</description></item><item><title>Longevity Forever</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/longevity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:55:20 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/longevity/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The joy cry resolved into a jubilating chant: “Long live the king! Long live us all!” The king’s advisors, like everybody that night, were as happy as children; they embraced each other and congratulated the king: “We did it! We did it!”
But the king answered in a broken voice: “Yes, we did it, we killed the dragon today. But damn, why did we start so late? This could have been done five, maybe ten years ago!</description></item><item><title>AI</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:39:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ai/</guid><description>We refer to the question: What sort of creature man’s next successor in the supremacy of the earth is likely to be. We have often heard this debated; but it appears to us that we are ourselves creating our own successors; we are daily adding to the beauty and delicacy of their physical organisation; we are daily giving them greater power and supplying by all sorts of ingenious contrivances that self-regulating, self-acting power which will be to them what intellect has been to the human race.</description></item><item><title>Seeking Idea Alpha</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/idea-alpha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:02:14 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/idea-alpha/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Here’s to the crazy ones, the misfits, the rebels, the troublemakers, the round pegs in the square holes… the ones who see things differently — they’re not fond of rules… You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them, but the only thing you can’t do is ignore them because they change things… they push the human race forward, and while some may see them as the crazy ones, we see genius, because the ones who are crazy enough to think that they can change the world, are the ones who do.</description></item><item><title>Status Quo</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/status-quo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:51:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/status-quo/</guid><description>Disclaimer This picture is a commentary on human sacrifice as a societal practice, nothing else.
“Whenever serious and competent people need to get things done in the real world, all considerations of tradition and protocol fly out the window.” ~ Neal Stephenson
The status quo is taken seriously for many reasons, because most people are conservative in a way that few ever state or articulate completely– This convention, institution, etc. is the right way because it is the way I know best.</description></item><item><title>Enterprising Investor</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/enterprising-investor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 16:38:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/enterprising-investor/</guid><description>Disclaimer I am not an investment advisor. None of the information presented herein is intended to form the basis of any offer or recommendation or have any regard to the investment objectives, financial situation, or needs of any specific person, and that includes you, my dear reader. Everything you’re going to read is for informational purposes only. PLEASE DO NOT ASK FOR ANY FINANCIAL ADVICE, MY ANSWER IS ALWAYS “I DO NOT GIVE ADVICE.</description></item><item><title>Increasing Happiness</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/increasing-happiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 22:57:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/increasing-happiness/</guid><description>The Science of Happiness While taking the science of well being course on coursera I decided to take the course quite seriously. For one, I started without taking any of my baseline assumptions for granted and applied my skepticism as best as I could to &amp;ldquo;commong knowledge&amp;rdquo; ways of looking at happiness.
Overall the course was a good start on a life long journey to find meaning and happiness. Many of the findings are common knowledge, but definitely not common practice.</description></item><item><title>Decreasing Consumption, Increasing Happiness</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/decreasing-consumption/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/decreasing-consumption/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time to stop pointing fingers, finger pointing gets us no-where, Steve!&amp;rdquo; ~ Randy Marsh, South Park
In the past year I have reduced my carbon footprint to about 10% that of an average American without much effort. How?
Before telling other people how to live, I have found it is a good idea to examine my life thoroughly first. I know, I know&amp;ndash; where is the fun in that?</description></item><item><title>Perspectives on Progress</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/perspectives-on-progress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/perspectives-on-progress/</guid><description>I have thought about progress for a long time and learned much. For one, I learned the business of forecasting is littered with fake experts and real experts that are easily separable when you put aside most authority and other logical fallacies and simply figure out who can demonstrate their abilities under measurable conditions. In fact, it turns out super forecasters are real and use many reliable techniques to get the job done.</description></item><item><title>Ultralearning</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ultralearning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ultralearning/</guid><description>Background We live in a time when you can go on the internet and read about most things to some level. So can you learning the equivalent to getting an undergraduate degree from a top university? Scott Young set out on a bold project of obtaining the equivalent knowledge of an undergraduate Computer Science degree from MIT in a year. He called this project the MIT Challenge. Did he succeed in this challenge?</description></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/digital-minimalism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/digital-minimalism/</guid><description>Background Something is wrong with us now days. Why is it so hard to deal with a bit of boredom or lack of stimulation from our smartphones? The answer goes deeper than many thought.
After going through Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s books: Deep Work and So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You I had to pick up his most recent work on the subject of software technology in our lives. This book isn&amp;rsquo;t just about getting work done, it is about getting your life back from companies who want your attention.</description></item><item><title>The Intelligent Investor</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/intelligent-investor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/intelligent-investor/</guid><description>Background Around 2014, after being recommended this book by numerous sources, I picked it up and gave it a read. Great books profoundly influence the way you think for the rest of your life. The Intelligent Investor is such a book. It challenged my initial ideas on investment, how to think about assets, and how to think about wealth. Contained within it are sound principles for first preserving what one has and then increase that pile of money safely with time.</description></item><item><title>Deep Work</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/deep-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/deep-work/</guid><description>The Gist that I got:
Create a place or places for deep work free of distraction for extended periods of well defined chunked work that are part of a strong formed habit with daily rituals of getting up and winding down. Each part of your day is segmented. Do not allow distractions or boredom to get in the way. Make sure your outside activities help support deep work meaning you don't extensively used social media, lots of video games, etc--these things train you for consistent attentional switching which is not part of deep work.</description></item><item><title>So Good They Can't Ignore You</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/so-good/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/so-good/</guid><description>Why is Following the Romantic Notion of Passion Bad Advice? I have read many books on productivity but this one stood out to me since the thesis was taking on a central dogma of a large portion of the US society: that following your passion is the key to happiness and fulfillment in the modern world. I have always been skeptical of this hypothesis, but I have not seen a well stated alternative worldview that does not have tremendous downsides.</description></item><item><title>The Originals</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-originals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-originals/</guid><description>I rarely come away from a book with some solid actionable insights but luckily for me this book had some stellar information and a solid data driven approach to viewing the power of original thinking.
A valuable cognitive strategy I learned from the book is called defensive pessimism which can be defined by wikipedia as:
&amp;quot;When implementing defensive pessimism, individuals set low expectations for their performance, regardless of how well they have done in the past.</description></item><item><title>The Willpower Instinct</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-willpower-instinct/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-willpower-instinct/</guid><description>Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5BXuZL1HAg
Sleep intervention — sleep more
mindfulness meditation + Physical exercise
Goal: Make willpower system (prefrontal cortex) bigger and better connected
Low glycemic plant based diet is ideal
Feeling guilty actually drains willpower so instead&amp;hellip;self-compassion message
Mindfulness of what you are thinking and feeling
Common humanity—everyone makes mistakes
Encouragement over criticism
learning how to talk to yourself as a good person, encouraging, and being nice</description></item><item><title>Learning How to Learn</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</guid><description>Metaskills Part 1: Learning to Learn Introduction Some of you may be aware where I picked up the term “metaskills” from, but I’ll state it anyway: Marty Neumeier’s book _Metaskills: Five Talents for the Robotic Age. _What is a metaskill? The basic idea is that a metaskill is a general skill that can be applied to numerous fields and disciplines. I thought the most important was, of course, the metaskill of all metaskills, learning to learn.</description></item><item><title>Algorithms to Live By</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/algorithms-to-live-by/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/algorithms-to-live-by/</guid><description>After listening to the 80,000 hours podcast episode 48 I realized that this book was right up my alley and decided it was worth a book review awhile ago but never put it together until now.
Key Concepts and Algorithms:
Optimal Stopping &amp;ndash; The Secretary Problem.
Optimal Stopping with full information (Threshold rule). Set a threshold and anyone over that threshold.
Multi-Armed Bandit Problem.</description></item><item><title>Transforming The Generic Interview</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/transforming-generic-interview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/transforming-generic-interview/</guid><description>Transforming Generic Interview Questions This is an ongoing culmination of general interviewing tips. I hope these are helpful to you as well.
1. Tell me about yourself “You are not your job, you’re not how much money you have in the bank. You are not the car you drive. You’re not the contents of your wallet.” ~ Fight Club
This is your moment to cover things not listed on your resume, don’t reiterate your resume!</description></item><item><title>Daily Lifestyle Checklist</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/daily-lifestyle-checklist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/daily-lifestyle-checklist/</guid><description>Disclaimer DISCLAIMER: THIS WEBSITE DOES NOT PROVIDE MEDICAL ADVICE The information, including but not limited to, text, graphics, images and other material contained on this website are for informational purposes only. No material on this site is intended to be a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. Always seek the advice of your physician or other qualified health care provider with any questions you may have regarding a medical condition or treatment and before undertaking a new health care regimen, and never disregard professional medical advice or delay in seeking it because of something you have read on this website.</description></item><item><title>Financial Matters</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/financial-matters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/financial-matters/</guid><description>Disclaimer I am simply an enthusiastic lay person who happens to know some math, a fair bit of personal finance, and likes reading on the topic. Please consult a professional who is qualified for specific advice related to your financial situation. This means I don&amp;rsquo;t want to answer YOUR specific questions and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into the weeds.
I prefer to teach people how to think about fishing, NOT even how to fish.</description></item></channel></rss>