<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>finance on Alexander Saavedra</title>
    <link>https://awsaavedra.com/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in finance on Alexander Saavedra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 16:38:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awsaavedra.com/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enterprising Investor</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/enterprising-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 16:38:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/enterprising-investor/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer I am not an investment advisor. None of the information presented herein is intended to form the basis of any offer or recommendation or have any regard to the investment objectives, financial situation, or needs of any specific person, and that includes you, my dear reader. Everything you’re going to read is for informational purposes only. PLEASE DO NOT ASK FOR ANY FINANCIAL ADVICE, MY ANSWER IS ALWAYS “I DO NOT GIVE ADVICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intelligent Investor</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/intelligent-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/intelligent-investor/</guid>
      <description>Background Around 2014, after being recommended this book by numerous sources, I picked it up and gave it a read. Great books profoundly influence the way you think for the rest of your life. The Intelligent Investor is such a book. It challenged my initial ideas on investment, how to think about assets, and how to think about wealth. Contained within it are sound principles for first preserving what one has and then increase that pile of money safely with time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Matters</title>
      <link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/financial-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/financial-matters/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer I am simply an enthusiastic lay person who happens to know some math, a fair bit of personal finance, and likes reading on the topic. Please consult a professional who is qualified for specific advice related to your financial situation. This means I don&amp;rsquo;t want to answer YOUR specific questions and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into the weeds.
I prefer to teach people how to think about fishing, NOT even how to fish.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
