<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>productivity on Alexander Saavedra</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in productivity on Alexander Saavedra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awsaavedra.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultralearning</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ultralearning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/ultralearning/</guid><description>Background We live in a time when you can go on the internet and read about most things to some level. So can you learning the equivalent to getting an undergraduate degree from a top university? Scott Young set out on a bold project of obtaining the equivalent knowledge of an undergraduate Computer Science degree from MIT in a year. He called this project the MIT Challenge. Did he succeed in this challenge?</description></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/digital-minimalism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/digital-minimalism/</guid><description>Background Something is wrong with us now days. Why is it so hard to deal with a bit of boredom or lack of stimulation from our smartphones? The answer goes deeper than many thought.
After going through Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s books: Deep Work and So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You I had to pick up his most recent work on the subject of software technology in our lives. This book isn&amp;rsquo;t just about getting work done, it is about getting your life back from companies who want your attention.</description></item><item><title>Deep Work</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/deep-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/deep-work/</guid><description>The Gist that I got:
Create a place or places for deep work free of distraction for extended periods of well defined chunked work that are part of a strong formed habit with daily rituals of getting up and winding down. Each part of your day is segmented. Do not allow distractions or boredom to get in the way. Make sure your outside activities help support deep work meaning you don't extensively used social media, lots of video games, etc--these things train you for consistent attentional switching which is not part of deep work.</description></item><item><title>So Good They Can't Ignore You</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/so-good/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/so-good/</guid><description>Why is Following the Romantic Notion of Passion Bad Advice? I have read many books on productivity but this one stood out to me since the thesis was taking on a central dogma of a large portion of the US society: that following your passion is the key to happiness and fulfillment in the modern world. I have always been skeptical of this hypothesis, but I have not seen a well stated alternative worldview that does not have tremendous downsides.</description></item><item><title>The Originals</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-originals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/the-originals/</guid><description>I rarely come away from a book with some solid actionable insights but luckily for me this book had some stellar information and a solid data driven approach to viewing the power of original thinking.
A valuable cognitive strategy I learned from the book is called defensive pessimism which can be defined by wikipedia as:
&amp;quot;When implementing defensive pessimism, individuals set low expectations for their performance, regardless of how well they have done in the past.</description></item><item><title>Algorithms to Live By</title><link>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/algorithms-to-live-by/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awsaavedra.com/posts/algorithms-to-live-by/</guid><description>After listening to the 80,000 hours podcast episode 48 I realized that this book was right up my alley and decided it was worth a book review awhile ago but never put it together until now.
Key Concepts and Algorithms:
Optimal Stopping &amp;ndash; The Secretary Problem.
Optimal Stopping with full information (Threshold rule). Set a threshold and anyone over that threshold.
Multi-Armed Bandit Problem.</description></item></channel></rss>